Daniel Huong

I'm a junior full stack developer who's passionate about creating clean, responsive web applications with the latest technologies. My past roles in the finance industry has given me analytical experience and a strong business acumen to compliment my coding skills. I am excited about my new career path into the world of tech and can't wait progress my skills.

36 Lakewood Bvd Cairnlea, VIC, 3023 **0421 119 005** daniel.huong86@gmail.com

Portfolio:

http://danielhuong.netlify.com/
Github:

https://github.com/miminum

EDUCATION

Coder Academy, Melbourne — Web Development, Fast Track Bootcamp Graduate

JULY 2017 - FEBRUARY 2018

University of Melbourne, Parkville — Bachelor of Commerce

FEBRUARY 2007 - JULY 2010

SKILLS

Web Development

- FrontEnd: ReactJS, HTML5, CSS, SASS/SCSS, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, Stylus, UI/UX, Figma
- BackEnd: Node.js, Ruby, SQL, MongoDB, Express.js
- Other: AWS(S3), Git, Figma, Trello, DbDesigner, Heroku, Netlify, mLab & Zeit's Now (MongoDB), RSpec
- Strong capabilities in producing responsive web apps from planning, to design, to production and review. Experienced using planning tools such as Figma to map out UX/UI, and deployment with various technologies.

Other

- Strong ability to prioritise large workloads with a can do attitude.
- Excellent analytical and problem solving skills developed at NAB as they were required to successfully find solutions for stakeholders.
- Well developed communication and interpersonal skills demonstrated in previous roles where I had to engage with clients and different levels of staff.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Lobster:

A 2-sided marketplace for home cooked meals. It is like a 2-sided uberEats where you can purchase local food and be a local cook; choosing when to work.

Links:

https://tasty-lobster.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/miminum/Lobster

Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, AWS(S3), SCSS, Heroku

Ruby Terminal Application:

"GroPro Hero" provides a solution track their vegetable and herb progress in their gardens. Received positive feedback for the impressive UI. My first CoderAcademy group assignment.

Links:

https://github.com/miminum/GroProHero

Technologies used: Ruby

Jitsmob:

A client project for Jitsmob, a company that aims to educate jiu jitsu and MMA enthusiasts on injury prevention & mobility.

Links: http://jitsmob-1-5.netlify.com/

https://github.com/igaboc/jitsmob v1.5

Technologies used: ReactJS, Node.js, express, MongoDB, HTML5, CSS, Netlify

EXPERIENCE

Alex Solutions, Melbourne — *Developer Internship*

FEBRUARY 2018 - MARCH 2018

- -Fixed bugs using SQL, Bash script, command line script.
- Built a frontend discussion/reply module in reactJS and using Material UI framework.
- Participated in team SCRUMs and Sprints under the AGILE methodology.

Metro Trains Melbourne, Melbourne — Penalty Fares Administrative Officer

OCTOBER 2015 - AUGUST 2016

- Data Entry, generating reports, administration duties.

National Australia Bank, Docklands — Customer Fulfillment Officer (NAB Broker Mortgages)

JULY 2013 - OCTOBER 2015

- Case management of clients in preparation for real estate settlements.
- Reduced risk exposure by understanding and implementing legal frameworks.

National Australia Bank, Melbourne — *Loan Modifications Officer*

JULY 2012 - JANUARY 2013

- Processed loan changes on NAB's backend systems.

McDonald's, Whistler, Canada — Crew Member

NOVEMBER 2011 - APRIL 2012

- Working holiday over the ski season.

Southgate Financial Services, South Melbourne — Fleet and Finance Consultant

OCTOBER 2010 - SEPTEMBER 2011

- Sold fleet and finance solutions to individual, business and not for profit clients.

Roy Morgan Research, Melbourne — CATI Interviewer (Computer Assisted Telephone Interviewing)

APRIL 2008 - AUGUST 2010

- Cold calling to complete telephone surveys for the 'Morgan-Gallop Poll'.

INTERESTS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

ALEX Solutions

-Was commended for discussion/reply module built during the internship.

NAB

- -Was awarded with "shining star" awards for my customer service.
- Worked and implemented process changes to improve team efficiency.

Snowboarding

- Participated in the 2017 'Mum's the word' rail jam.
- Landed my first backflip in 2017.

Travel

- Took a career break in 2016 to travel to Europe for a backpacking trip. The highlight of the trip was witnessing the northern lights in Iceland.

REFEREES

Nezih Gizli - Head of Product & Operations, ALEX Solutions

nezih.gizli@alexsolutions.com.au 0450 251 205

Patrick Smith - Lead Educator, Coder Academy

patrick@burntcaramel.com

0448 525 425

Petula Mendes - Team Leader, Penalty Fares Administration Metro Trains Melbourne petula.mendes@metrotrains.com.au 0430 594 278

James Vargas — Team Leader, Customer Fulfillment National Australia Bank james.vargas@nab.com.au (03) 8614 0580